Owen Lattimore Papers
Manuscript Division, Library of Congress
Owen Lattimore Papers 1907-1997 (bulk 1950-1989)
MSS80712
Lattimore, Owen, 1900-1989
22,175 items
62 containers
27.1 linear feet
Manuscript Division, Library of Congress Washington, D.C.
Orientalist, author, educator, and historian. Correspondence, journals, writings, reviews, speeches, research notes, interviews, reports, transcripts of hearings, and other papers pertaining to Lattimore's studies in Chinese and Mongolian history and linguistics, his appointment as a political advisor to Chiang Kai-shek, and his service as director of Pacific Operations in the United States Office of War Information Overseas Operations Branch, and as a member of the United States Reparations Mission to Japan. Other topics include accusations by Senator Joseph R. McCarthy and subsequent Senate Foreign Relations Committee investigations (1951), and the establishment of the Lattimore Institute for Mongolian Studies.
Selected Search Terms
The following terms have been used to index the description of this collection in the LC Catalog. They are grouped by name of person or organization, by subject or location, and by occupation and listed alphabetically.
People
Barnes, Joseph, 1907-1970--Correspondence.; Barrett, Robert LeMoyne, 1871-1969--Correspondence.; Bernhard, Arnold, 1901-1987--Correspondence.; Burton, Stanley H.--Correspondence.; Carruthers, Rosemary--Correspondence.; Casseres, Isabel--Correspondence.; Chiang, Kai-shek, 1887-1975--Correspondence.; Childs, G. Herbert (George Herbert)--Correspondence.; Currie, Lauchlin Bernard--Correspondence.; Diluv Khutagt, 1884-1964--Correspondence.; Ecsedy, Ildikó--Correspondence.; Fairbank, John King, 1907-1991--Correspondence.; Glahn, Else--Correspondence.; Grebenik, Elvebeuck--Correspondence.; Heissig, Walther, 1913-2005--Correspondence.; Humphrey, Caroline--Correspondence.; Isono, Fujiko, 1918- --Correspondence.; Lattimore, Eleanor Holgate, 1895-1970. Eleanor Holgate Lattimore papers.; Lattimore, Owen, 1900-1989.; McCarthy, Joseph, 1908-1957--Correspondence.; Needham, Joseph, 1900-1995--Correspondence.; Nef, John U. (John Ulric), 1899-1988--Correspondence.; Newman, Robert P.--Correspondence.; Onon, Urgunge--Correspondence.; Piel, Gerard--Correspondence.; Richards, Margaret L.--Correspondence.; Roosevelt, Franklin D. (Franklin Delano), 1882-1945--Correspondence.; Snow, Edgar, 1905-1972--Correspondence.; Stefansson, Vilhjalmur, 1879-1962--Correspondence.; Toynbee, Arnold, 1889-1975--Correspondence.
Organizations
Lattimore Institute for Mongolian Studies.; United States. Congress. Senate. Committee on Foreign Relations.; United States. Office of War Information. Overseas Operations Branch.; United States. Reparations Mission to Japan.
Subjects
Communism--United States.; Internal security--United States.; Linguistics--China.; Linguistics--Mongolia.; Sino-Japanese War, 1937-1945.; Subversive activities.; World War, 1939-1945--Campaigns--Pacific Ocean.
Places
China--Foreign relations--United States.; China--History.; Japan--Foreign relations--United States.; Mongolia--History.; United States--Foreign relations--1933-1945.; United States--Foreign relations--1945-1953.; United States--Foreign relations--China.; United States--Foreign relations--Japan.
Occupations
Authors.; Educators.; Historians.; Orientalists.
Provenance
The papers of Owen Lattimore, Orientalist, author, historian, and educator, were deposited in the Library of Congress by the Lattimore Institute for Mongolian Studies in October 1990. An addition was given by Robert Newman in 1997.
Additional Guides
A description of the Lattimore Papers appears in Library of Congress Acquisitions: Manuscript Division, 1990, pp. 19-23.
Transfers
Items have been transferred from the Manuscript Division to other custodial divisions of the Library. Books and an opera playbill have been transferred to the Asian Division. A map has been transferred to the Geography and Map Division. A motion picture film has been transferred to the Motion Picture, Broadcasting, and Recorded Sound Division. Some photographs have been transferred to the Prints and Photographs Division. All transfers are identified in these divisions as part of the Owen Lattimore Papers.
Related Material
Researchers may wish to consult collections of Lattimore's papers preserved at other depositories, including the archives of Johns Hopkins University, University of Leeds, and Dartmouth College. Records documenting Lattimore's association with the American Institute of Pacific Relations and its journal Pacific Affairs, which Lattimore edited from 1934 to 1941, can be found at Columbia University. While the Library of Congress does have many books authored by Lattimore, his personal library was donated to the Brotherton Library at the University of Leeds, and his collection of Oriental anthropological artifacts was deposited with the Peabody Museum of Archaeology and Ethnology at Harvard University.
Access and Restrictions
The papers of Owen Lattimore are open to research. Researchers are advised to contact the Manuscript Reading Room prior to visiting. Many collections are stored off-site and advance notice is needed to retrieve these items for research use.
Biographical Note
Date Event
1900, July 29 Born, Washington, D.C.
1913 1914 Attended College Classique Cantonal, Lausanne, Switzerland
1915 1919 Attended St. Bees School, Cumberland, England
1920 Engaged in export-import business in Shanghai, China
1921 Assistant editor of newspaper in Tientsin, China
1922 1926 Employed by Arnold & Co., Tientsin and Peking, China
1926 Married Eleanor Holgate of Evanston, Ill.
1926 1927 Traveled with his wife by rail and camel from Peking, China, through Inner Mongolia, the Etsin Gol, the Black Gobi, and Kashmir, Pakistan, to Bombay, India, then by ship to Italy
1928 1929 Attended Harvard Graduate School, Cambridge, Mass., and Harvard-Yenching Institute, Yenching, China
1929 1930 Researched in Manchuria under Social Sciences Research Council
1930 1931 Researched in Peiping, China, under Harvard-Yenching Institute, Yenching, China
1931 1933 Researched under J. S. Guggenheim Memorial Foundation, New York, N.Y.
1934 1937 Field work in Mongolia and research in Peiping, China, under Institute of Pacific Relations
1934 1941 Editor, Pacific Affairs
1938 1963 Lecturer, Johns Hopkins University, Baltimore, Md.
1939 1953 Director, Walter Hines Page School of International Relations, Johns Hopkins University, Baltimore, Md.
1941 1942 Political advisor to Chiang Kai-shek
1942 1944 Director, Pacific Operations, United States Office of War Information
1945 1946 Member, United States Reparations Mission to Japan
1950 Chief, United Nations Technical Aid Exploratory Mission to Afghanistan
1951 Investigated by Senate Foreign Relations Committee as a communist sympathizer and Soviet spy; indicted on seven counts of perjury
1955 Perjury indictments dismissed by United States District Court
1958 1959 Visiting lectureships, Vlieme Section, Ecole Pratique des Hautes Etudes, Paris, France
1963 1970 Professor of Chinese Studies, University of Leeds, Leeds, England
1965 Chichele Lecturer, Oxford University, Oxford, England
1982 Visiting Professor, Rutgers University, New Brunswick, N.J.
1989, May 31 Died, Providence, R.I.
Scope and Content Note
The papers of Owen Lattimore (1900-1989) span the years 1907-1997, with the bulk of the items concentrated in the period from 1950 to 1989. The collection relates to both private and professional matters and is arranged in seven series, the largest of which--constituting one-third of the collection--is General Correspondence. The Wartime Activities series includes records documenting Lattimore's service as a political advisor to Chiang Kai-shek, director of the Pacific Operations of the United States War Information Office, and a member of the United States Reparations Mission to Japan. Another large series, Senate Hearings, contains correspondence and records documenting Lattimore's defense against Republican Senator Joseph McCarthy's charges that he participated in communist espionage during the 1940s. Also in the collection is a Speeches and Writings series that includes articles, book reviews, and texts of Lattimore's speeches and lectures. Notable in the Miscellany series are Lattimore's handwritten journals on his pioneer trips to the inner-Asian borderlands during the 1920s and 1930s. The remaining series are titled: Subject File, Eleanor Holgate Lattimore File, Addition, and Oversize.
Records in the collection chronicling Lattimore's field research and travels in Peiping (China), Mongolia, and Manchuria during the 1920s and 1930s are particularly comprehensive. In addition to the aforementioned journals, the Subject File contains transcribed notes of Lattimore's ethnographic, historical, and cultural observations made during his travels, including information on the languages and dialects of the region. Lattimore's extensive travels in Asia provided the basis for many of his writings, which together with the related correspondence with publishers, form another strong element of the collection. Among these writings is an unpublished and incomplete autobiographical sketch, "Happiness Is Among Strangers."
Another integral component of the collection is Owen and Eleanor Lattimore's expansive correspondence, both incoming and outgoing, with colleagues, family, and friends. Many Oriental and Asian scholars, publishers, and professional colleagues are represented, including Isabel Casseres, Lauchlin Bernard Currie, Diluv Khutagt, Ildikó Ecsedy, Else Glahn, Elvebeuck Grebenik, Walther Heissig, Caroline Humphrey, Fujiko Isono, John Ulric Nef, Robert P. Newman, Urgunge Onon, Edgar B. Snow, Vilhjalmur Stefansson, and Arnold Joseph Toynbee. There is also considerable correspondence of many of Lattimore's personal friends and advisors, including Joseph Barnes, Robert LeMoyne Barrett, Arnold Bernhard, Stanley H. Burton, Rosemary Carruthers, G. Herbert Childs, John King Fairbank, Joseph Needham, Gerard Piel, and Margaret L. Richards. There is lengthy correspondence with his son David and his brother Richmond, as well as letters of his lawyers and accountants, especially William Dill Rogers and Nancy K. Mintz, which document his investments, estate settlements, establishment of the Lattimore Institute for Mongolian Studies, and litigious fallout from his Senate investigations.
Material documenting Lattimore's appointment by President Franklin D. Roosevelt as an advisor to the Chinese Nationalist government in Chungking during World War II is scant. Although there are summaries of conversations, biographical assessments, and advisory reports prepared for Chiang Kai-shek, these files are incomplete. Of particular importance, however, is the considerable correspondence between Lattimore and Lauchlin Bernard Currie of the State Department concerning the war against Japan and the problems of American assistance to the Chinese war effort. There is evidence that late in his life Lattimore, with the assistance of his lawyers and Robert P. Newman, sought to obtain through the Freedom of Information Act copies of government records documenting his tenure in Chungking, to supplement and complete his personal papers.
Files documenting the Senate's investigation of espionage and conspiracy charges against Lattimore are extensive. In 1950 Joseph R. McCarthy described Lattimore as the "chief architect" of a United States foreign policy that resulted in the Communist party's conquest of mainland China. McCarthy accused Lattimore of being the "top Soviet agent in the United States." Lattimore denied the charges, and a Senate committee initially vindicated him. Additional accusations were made a year later, however, and the Justice Department twice brought indictments against Lattimore on perjury charges stemming from his earlier testimony. The indictments were later dismissed in federal court. Preserved in the Senate Hearings series is correspondence with Lattimore's legal advisors, academic colleagues, and the public concerning the testimony. Also available are an extensive file of newspaper clippings and magazine articles, reports, hearing transcripts, motions, memoranda, opinions, and other documents relating to the perjury charges and Congressional investigation.
Organization of the Papers
The collection is arranged in nine series:
General Correspondence, 1929-1988
Subject File, 1907-1979
Wartime Activities, 1934-1973
Senate Hearings, 1910-1988
Speeches and Writings, 1920-1987
Miscellany, 1922-1991
Eleanor Holgate Lattimore Files, 1924-1970
Addition, 1970, 1997
Oversize, 1931-1971
Container List
- General Correspondence, 1929-1988 (Box 1-22)
  Professional and personal correspondence, both incoming and outgoing.
  Arranged alphabetically by name of individual or corporate entity, and thereunder by date in reverse chronological order. Note that correspondence of an individual may be found either under the person's name or under the names of organizations which the person represented. An alphabetical listing of all correspondents is filed at the beginning of this series.
  - Index of correspondents (Box 1)
  - A. W. Bain & Sons Limited, 1963-1978, undated
  - Academy of Sciences of the Mongolian People's Republic, Ulan-Bator, Mongolia, 1969-1987, undated
  - American Council of Learned Societies, 1960-1967, undated
  - American Ethnologist, 1985-1986
  - American Philosophical Society, 1962-1986, undated
  - AMS Press, 1970-1984, undated
  - Andrews, Robert A. and Eleanor, 1950-1986, undated
  - Anglo-Mongolian Society, London, England, 1981-1985, undated
  - Arnold & Porter, 1955-1980
  - Arnold Bernhard & Co.
    - Aug. 1957-Aug. 1986, (3 folders)
    - Oct. 1955-July 1957, undated (Box 2)
  - Arnoldo Mondadori Co., 1984-1985
  - Asia Magazine, 1930
  - Atlantic Monthly Press, 1929-1986
  - "A" miscellaneous, 1956-1987, undated, (2 folders)
  - Barnes, Joseph and Betty, 1934-1986, undated
  - Barrett, Robert LeMoyne and Katharine Ellis
    - 1940-1972, undated, (3 folders)
    - Undated, (2 folders) (Box 3)
  - Beer, William A. and Katharine, 1956-1988
  - Bernhard, Arnold See Container 1, Arnold Bernhard & Co.
  - Black, Ian E. and Raymond, 1962-1984, undated
  - Blunden, Jane and Caroline, 1979-1987
  - Boas, George and Simone, 1957-1980
  - Borg, Dorothy, 1955-1976, undated
  - Bothe, Elsbeth Levy, 1956-1983, undated
  - Bray, William G., 1973
  - Brechers, Edward and Ruth, 1956-1964
  - Brown, W. N. and Helen, 1958-1975
  - Brown University, Providence, R.I., 1974-1987
  - Bunge, William, 1973-1987
  - Burton, Stanley H., 1967-1986
  - "B" miscellaneous
    - Ba-Be, 1948-1983, undated
    - Bi-Bu, 1941-1987, undated, (2 folders) (Box 4)
  - Cambridge University, Cambridge, England, 1967-1985
  - Campion, Brenda, 1982-1984
  - Carruthers, Rosemary, 1968-1987, undated, (3 folders)
  - Casseres, Isabel, 1949-1971, undated
  - Chabros, Krystyna, 1984-1987, undated
  - Childs, G. Herbert and Margaret, 1963-1970
  - Clubb, O. Edmund, 1958-1970
  - Colvin, John, 1973-1986
  - Conner, Helene A., 1970-1979
  - Cotton, James and Fiona, 1980-1984
  - Cowan, Lester and Ann Ronell, 1955-1966, undated (Box 5)
  - Craig, Albert B., Jr., and Sybil, 1956-1970, undated
  - Currie, Lauchlin Bernard, 1969-1984
  - "C" miscellaneous, 1934-1988, undated, (4 folders)
  - Debevoise, Plimpton, Lyons & Gates, 1972-1980, (3 folders)
  - DeFrancis, John, 1964-1986
  - Diehl, Lois, 1957-1964, undated
  - Diluv Khutagt, 1932-1956, undated
  - District of Columbia, 1978-1985 (Box 6)
  - Douglas, William O. and Mercedes, 1961-1962, undated
  - Dragadze-Klimiashvilly, Tamara ("Tamir") 1970-1984, undated
  - "D" miscellaneous, 1944-1984, undated, (2 folders)
  - Ecole Pratique des Hautes Études, Paris, France, 1960-1970, undated
  - Ecsedy, Ildikó, 1963-1987
  - Encyclopaedia Britannica, 1968-1987
  - Epstein, Israel and Elsie Fairfax-Cholmeley, 1984
  - "E" miscellaneous, 1950-1985, undated, (2 folders)
  - Fairbank, John King and Wilma, 1956-1987, undated
  - Fairfax County, Va., 1973-1986
  - Finkelstein, David J., 1970-1984, undated
  - Fletcher, Joseph F., 1966-1975
  - Foer, Kathy, 1982-1983
  - Ford & Warren
    - 1980-1986
    - 1968-1979 (Box 7)
  - Francis & Co., 1974-1987
  - Frost, Marguerite ("Muggsie"), 1975-1978, undated
  - Frye, Stanley and Mary, 1964-1983
  - "F" miscellaneous, 1935-1987, undated, (2 folders)
  - Gertler, Maynard and Ann, 1963-1974, undated
  - Glahn, Else, 1962-1985, undated, (2 folders)
  - Graves, Mortimer and Jane, 1950-1973
  - Great Britain, official government correspondence
    - 1949-1983, undated
  - Grebenik, Elvebeuck, 1962-1984
  - "G" miscellaneous
    - Ga-Gol, 1960-1987, undated
    - Goo-Gu, 1956-1987, undated (Box 8)
  - Hangin, John G. and Linda, 1954-1980
  - Harris, Beach & Wilcox, 1968-1972, undated
  - Harvard University, Cambridge, Mass., 1929-1986, undated
  - Heissig, Walther and Annemarie, 1961-1987, undated
  - Hertzman, Owen, 1986-1988
  - Holgate, Francis B., 1950-1978
  - Holland, William L. and Doreen, 1966-1986
  - Humphrey, Caroline, 1970-1988
  - "H" miscellaneous
    - Ha-Hov, 1950-1987, undated, (4 folders)
    - Hs-Hy, 1955-1986, undated (Box 9)
  - International Congress of Mongolists, Ulan-Bator, Mongolia, 1970-1987, undated
  - Isono, Fujiko, 1969-1987, undated, (3 folders)
  - "I" miscellaneous, 1946-1986, undated
  - Johns Hopkins University, Baltimore, Md., 1936-1974, undated
  - "J" miscellaneous, 1939-1984, undated
  - Kirwan, Lawrence and Stella, 1958-1987, undated
  - Klareich, Stephanie, 1979-1982, undated
  - Kuznets, Simon and Edith, 1955-1985, undated
  - "K" miscellaneous, 1955-1987, undated, (2 folders) (Box 10)
  - Lattimore, David and Emily Sargent
    - 1942-1987, (4 folders)
    - Undated, (2 folders)
    - Undated (Box 11)
  - Lattimore, David and Margaret Barnes, 1935, undated
  - Lattimore, Eleanor Holgate, 1957-1966, undated
  - Lattimore, Richmond, lecture, 1957
  - Lattimore, Richmond and Alice, 1952-1987, undated
  - Lattimore grandchildren, 1968-1987, undated
  - Lennox, H. H. and Doreen, 1956-1973, undated
  - Lewis, Wilfred Sargent and Carol, 1955-1962, undated, (2 folders)
  - Library of Congress, Copyright Office, 1929-1956
  - Long & Foster Realtors, Fairfax, Va., 1980-1988
  - "L" miscellaneous, 1956-1987, undated, (2 folders)
  - Machlup, Fritz and Mitzi, 1959-1964, undated (Box 12)
  - Madison National Bank, 1970-1986, undated
  - Manufacturers Life Insurance Co., 1938-1971
  - McCarthy, Charlotte Barnes, 1955-1980, undated
  - Merrill Lynch, Pierce, Fenner & Smith, 1963-1988, undated, (2 folders)
  - Mintz, Nancy K.
    - 1978-1988, (9 folders)
    - 1970-1977, undated, (6 folders) (Box 13)
  - Mongolia Society, Bloomington, Ind., 1965-1987
  - Mongolian People's Republic, 1964-1987, undated
  - Monnot, Kay J., 1984-1986
  - Month, 1977-1982
  - Morgan, Gerry, 1967-1977, undated
  - Moser, LeRoy G., 1986-1988
  - "M" miscellaneous
    - Ma-May, 1951-1987, n.d
    - Mc-My, 1950-1988, undated, (2 folders) (Box 14)
  - N. V. Boekhandel en Drukkerij v/h E. J. Brill, 1969-1975
  - National Westminster Bank PLC, 1967-1986, undated
  - Needham, Joseph, 1962-1981
  - Nef, John Ulric and Evelyn Schwartz Baird, 1964-1987, undated, (2 folders)
  - New York Times, 1967-1987
  - Newman, Robert P., 1977-1987
  - Nixon, Andrea, 1980-1987
  - "N" miscellaneous, 1939-1987, undated, (2 folders)
  - O'Brien, Marguerite, 1955-1977, undated
  - Olcott, Martha Brill, 1978-1981
  - Onon, Urgunge and Narangerel, 1963-1987, undated (Box 15)
  - Oxford University Press, 1960-1981
  - "O" miscellaneous, 1954-1987, undated
  - Pacific Affairs, 1973-1983, undated
  - Parsons, Carol D., 1974-1979
  - People's Republic of China, 1963-1983, undated
  - Peters Elworthy & Moore, 1980-1987
  - Pruitt, Ida, 1952-1970, undated
  - "P" miscellaneous, 1947-1988, undated, (2 folders)
  - "Q" miscellaneous, 1961-1975, undated
  - Richards, Margaret L., 1974-1987
  - Richey, Murray R., 1977-1979, undated, (2 folders)
  - Riggs National Bank, 1982-1987, undated (Box 16)
  - Riznik, Barnes and Diana Smith, 1959-1970, undated
  - Riznik, Charlotte Barnes, 1954-1988, undated, (2 folders)
  - Rogers, William Dill and Suzanne ("Suki")
    - 18 Sept. 1970-23 Mar. 1987, (8 folders)
    - 30 July 1956-14 Sept. 1970, undated, (8 folders) (Box 17)
  - Rosenbaum, Francis N. and Jane C., 1970-1971, undated
  - Royal Geographical Society (Great Britain), 1962-1987
  - Rutgers University, New Brunswick, N.J., 1978-1987
  - "R" miscellaneous
    - Ra-Ro, 1953-1987, undated, (2 folders)
    - Ru-Ry, 1954-1986, (1 folder) (Box 18)
  - Samuel L. Silber & Co., 1963-1987, undated, (3 folders)
  - Scientific American, 1956-1987, undated, (3 folders)
  - Seward, Ralph T. and Clayton ("Swiss"), 1955-1987, undated
  - Shelesnyak, Moses Chiem and Roslyn, 1955-1964, undated
  - Singer, André, 1987
  - Sloan, William R. and Queenie, 1970-1984
  - Smithson, Blackburn & Co., 1964-1968
  - Snow, Edgar B. and Lois Wheeler, 1965-1987, undated
  - Société Générale, 1977-1983
  - Sotheby Parke Bernet & Co., 1978-1980
  - Southdown Community, Great Falls, Va., 1971-1987
  - Stefansson, Vilhjalmur and Evelyn Schwartz Baird
    - Dec. 1958-Nov. 1966
    - July 1949-Nov. 1958, undated, (5 folders) (Box 19)
  - "S" miscellaneous, 1950-1988, undated, (5 folders)
  - Thomas, Alice I. ("Tommy"), 1956-1983, undated
  - Thomas, Carrie, 1955-1963, undated
  - Thorner, Daniel and Alice, 1970-1987, undated (Box 20)
  - Toynbee, Arnold Joseph, 1958-1974, undated
  - Turnbulls (Removals) Ltd., 1974-1979
  - "T" miscellaneous, 1941-1986, undated, (3 folders)
  - United Nations, 1949-1950
  - United States government agencies, 1964-1985, undated, (2 folders)
  - University Microfilms International, 1970-1978, undated
  - University of California Press, 1969-1980, undated
  - University of Leeds, Leeds, England
    - Brotherton Library, 1962-1973
    - Department of Chinese Studies, 1962-1987
    - Miscellany, 1962-1984, undated
  - University of Leeds, Leeds, England
    - Office of the Bursar, 1962-1985, undated
    - Office of the Registrar, 1962-1984 (Box 21)
    - Office of the Vice-Chancellor, 1962-1983
    - School of History, 1981-1982
  - University of London, London, England, 1966-1968
  - "U" miscellaneous, 1950-1982, undated
  - "V" miscellaneous, 1955-1987, undated
  - Wenner-Gren Foundation for Anthropological Research
    - 1961-1978, undated
  - Who's Who, London, England, 1974-1981, undated
  - Wright, Arthur Frederick and Mary Clabaugh, 1956-1971, undated
  - "W" miscellaneous, 1956-1987, undated, (2 folders)
  - Young, Barbara, 1952-1980, undated, (2 folders)
  - "Y" miscellaneous, 1957-1982, undated
  - Ziggas, Alex R., 1970
  - "Z" miscellaneous, 1976-1985
  - Unidentified (Box 22)
    - English language, 1950-1986, undated, (5 folders)
    - Foreign language, 1943-1987, undated, (6 folders)
- Subject File, 1907-1979 (Box 22-26)
  Primarily research notes on Chinese and Mongolian history and linguistic studies and vocabularies of Mongol dialects. Additional material on the Inner Mongolian Autonomous Movement, World Youth Festival, and Joint Gobi Expedition. Of particular interest is a copy of Douglas Carruthers's journals, 1907-1911.
  Arranged alphabetically by topic.
  - Asian bibliography, undated (Box 22)
  - Carruthers, Douglas, journals (Box 23)
    - Aug. 1907-June 1908
      - Copy set A, (2 folders)
      - Copy set B, (2 folders)
    - July-Oct. 1908
      - Copy set A, (2 folders)
      - Copy set B
    - Apr.-Sept. 1910
      - Copy set A, (2 folders)
      - Copy set B, (2 folders)
    - Sept. 1910-June 1911
      - Copy set A, (2 folders)
      - Copy set B, (2 folders) (Box 24)
    - June-Nov. 1911
      - Copy set A
      - Copy set B
  - China
    - Fuchinhsien notes, undated
    - Historical material, notes and translations